# Manali Desai

# User Experience Designer

+1 (321) 525-5762

manaliuxd@gmail.com

http://www.linkedin.com/in/manalid

https://dmanali.github.io/portfolio/

Overall 12+ years of IT experience in designing and developing end to end enterprise applications in different domains like CRM, Insurance, Health, Hospitality. Working in the Insurance domain as a UX Generalist that allows me to perform job duties of a Designer and Information Architect. Development experience brings a value to the team to understand the design feasibility and collaborate with the product teams efficiently.

# **Work Experience**

### UX Generalist, Ciber LLC, IL

October 2018 - Till Date

- Two of my novel design ideas on task notification, creation, and assignment as a co-author are pending patent application
- Worked for State Farm Insurance in the consulting capacity to deliver user experiences for major efforts built on Salesforce Lightning platform
- Successfully delivered Auto and Renters bundle checkout experience starting with conceptualization to handover to the development teams
- Instrumental in carving out ideal experience to display Household information of a customer for Agents and Sales Associates
- Planned, conducted usability tests under the guidance of a senior Experience Researcher at State Farm
- Created onboarding material for team members on Salesforce Lightning Platform and onboarded 8 team members.
- Researched and designed self-service portal for agents and team members

#### UX Designer, Xoriant Infotech, CA

May 2018 - October 2018

- Worked with Apple Support Website team to create a functional prototype for customer satisfaction survey
- · Worked closely with Accessibility team to learn WCAG Accessibility Standards and how to incorporate them in the design even before the development starts.
- Worked with the product managers to understand the requirements and create UX wireframes, present concepts for an internal product that logs customer issues.
- Understanding the accessibility pain points and master the technique to address these issues during design phase. Evaluate the interactive prototype with Accessibility team and incorporate the feedback to accommodate WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) standards

#### UX Designer, Idea Helix Inc, CA

October 17 – May 2018

- Redesigned the existing MVP to optimize the Hiring Manager workflow and visualize the workforce status, Email Templates and Product Website
- Designed workflows and wireframes
- Designed High Fidelity Prototype using Material Design guidelines

### UX Designer, Indiana University, IN

January 16 - May 17

- Conducted user interviews to understand and validate the requirements
- Designed wireframes, User flows for the responsive website and for iPad
- Developed a responsive website using HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap
- Designed Surveys, Test Plans to conduct User Testing
- Created user evaluation and recommendations report

#### UX Design Intern, IDeaS (a SAS Company), MN

May 16 - August 16

- Taken primary responsibility for this UX project and working with product managers and software engineers to understand requirements
- Research and document mobile design standards in order to help define/refine existing standards.
- Designed workflows and low fidelity prototype as per iOS Human Interface Guidelines and iOS Design Patterns using Balsamiq and Justinmind

# Senior Software Engineer, EMC<sup>2</sup>, India

June 14 - July 15

- Performed a role of UI Designer to redesign and developed the onboarding flows and report filters
- In the role of a Web Developer, worked on the feature enhancements, maintenance of the plugin and troubleshoot production issue for Nokia Client

#### Senior Software Engineer, IDeaS (a SAS Company), India

April 13 - May 14

Collaborated with remote development team and UX Designers to migrate the existing Flex, HTML modules to Vaadin (HTML5/Java framework)

- Created a complex JQuery based dialog box component to incorporate the whole functionality of Information Manager module which appears on other Flex
  modules to resolve the information alerts.
- Worked in a highly agile team environment that made an independent development team

#### Associate, Cognizant Technology Solutions, India

June 11 - April 13

- Lead development effort for redesigning of G3 Application, received appreciation from UX Design team Won the Alliance Award
- Trained internal project team members on Adobe Flex/ActionScript avoiding the need for external training programs Won Championship Award

#### Front-end Developer, Sungard Technology Solutions, India

January 2011 to May 2011

- · Design, develop individual Flex components and frameworks to cater the common requirements of all the Bank Teams
- Learnt and implemented Pure MVC framework to create a Link bar component

### Software Engineer, Persistent Systems Ltd., India

January 08 - January 11

- · Part of the independent agile development team and Flex Competency Center to develop multiple POCs and Fixed Cost projects
- Lead a UI development team for Adobe e-Signature project Won Spot Award

#### Education

- MS Human Computer Interaction, Indiana University, IN, May 2017 | GPA 4.0
- Master of Computer Application, University of Pune, India, June 2008
- M.Sc. Instrumentation Science, University of Pune, India , June 1998

# **UX Designing Skills**

#### **Design Methodologies**

- User Research Contextual Inquiry, Interviews, Surveys, Observations
- Interaction Design Wireframes, Mock-ups, Prototyping
- Usability Evaluation Usability Testing

#### **Design Tools**

Sketch/Invision, Axure RP 9, Figma, Omnigraffle, Balsamiq, Justinmind, Mural, Zeplin, Adobe CC tools

# **Programming Skills**

Flex/ActionScript, HTML/CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, D3 JS,

# Project Management Skills

Agile Methodology, Rally, Version One, Subversion, GIT, CVS, Bugzilla, JIRA, BitBucket